truevalue.com 2018-04-24

# True Value: Privacy & Security

## Privacy Policy

  * Our Official Privacy Policy
  * Collection of Personal Information
  * Use of Personal Information
  * Call Centers
  * Online Registration
  * Passwords
  * Privacy Preferences / Opt-Out
  * Contests, Questions or Surveys

## Security Measures on Our Site

  * General
  * Protecting Children's Privacy
  * Information Sharing
  * Sale of Business
  * Legal
  * Tracking Tools
  * Third Party Links
  * How to Contact Us
  * Changes to the Privacy and Security Statement

  * This privacy policy outlines what information is gathered about you, how that information may be used and your choices in how that information is used. We may change or add to this privacy policy so we encourage you to review it periodically. 
  * This policy applies to True Value Company and its wholly owned subsidiaries. This policy will not apply to True Value retail stores unless there is a link to the policies on the retailer's website. True Value retail stores are independently owned and operated. True Value Company is not legally liable for actions taken by its retail stores. 
  * By using this site, our call centers and True Value locations you are agreeing to the terms of the privacy policy in effect at that time

If you have any questions about this policy please Contact Us.

## Collection of Personal Information

When you purchase items here, we gather the following information from you in order to fulfill and track your order.

  * Your name
  * Recipient name
  * Shipping address
  * Your billing address
  * Your email address
  * Your phone number
  * Your credit card number

We may also collect information in the following ways:

  * **Contact Information:** We may collect the names and user names of our customers and other visitors. Additionally, we may collect your purchase history, billing and shipping addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, and other digital contact information. We may also collect information that you provide us about others. 
  * **Payment Information:**  
When you make a purchase we collect your payment information, including information from your credit or debit card, check, PayPal account or gift card. If you apply for a True Value credit card, we might collect information related to your application. 
  * **Demographic Information:**  
We may collect information about products or services you like, reviews you submit, or where you shop. We might also collect information like your age or gender. 
  * **Location Information:**  
If you use our mobile services, we may collect location data obtained from your mobile device's GPS. If you use our websites, we may collect location data obtained from your IP address. We use this location data to find the True Value store nearest to you, product availability at the True Value stores near you and driving directions to True Value stores. 
  * **Other Information:**  
If you use our websites, we may collect information about the browser you are using. We might track the pages you visit, look at what website you came from, or what website you visit when you leave us. We collect this information using the tracking tools described in the Tracking Tools section at the bottom of this page. To control those tools, please read the Your Privacy Preferences section. 
  * **We collect information from you passively.** We may use tracking tools like browser cookies, flash cookies, and web beacons.
  * **We collect information from other sources.** We may get information about you from third party business partners, like demographic information We may collect information about you from a friend. For example, if your friend purchases something for us to send to you. 
  * **Contests, Questions or Surveys.** When you ask a question, participate in a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes we may collect your name, address, phone number and email address. We use this information to facilitate your participation in a contest or sweepstakes. At that time, we may ask your permission to send you future marketing information from TrueValue.com. 

## Use of Personal Information

We use the information we collect for our business purposes, including:

**To respond to your questions and requests.** Examples include:

  * Fulfilling orders or providing services 
  * Registering you for a particular website, loyalty program, or providing you with information regarding such programs or services 
  * Processing a return 
  * Responding to a product or service review
  * Entering you into a sweepstakes or sending you prizes you might have won.
  * **To improve our products and services.** We may use your information to make website or product and service improvements.
  * **To look at website trends and customer interests.** We might use your information to customize your experience with us. We may also combine information we get from you with information about you we have received from third parties to assess trends and interests. 

**For security purposes**  
We may use your information to protect our company, our customers, or our websites if we suspect fraud or other illegal activities or if there is an investigation relating to the same. 

**For our marketing**  
In certain circumstances, we may send you communications about special promotions or offers. For example, if you have registered on a website and indicated you want to receive this information. We may also notify you of new website features or product and service offerings. If permitted, we may also send information about offers from our Affiliates and other companies we think you might find interesting. To manage our communications with you, follow the instructions in the Your Privacy Preferences section below. 

**To communicate with you about your account or our relationship**  
We may contact you to tell you about changes to this Privacy and Security Statement, the Terms of Use of our websites or mobile services, or changes to any of our programs in which you might be enrolled. We may also tell you about issues with your orders or if there is a product recall. 

**For other uses we may disclose to you.**

## Additional Security Info You Should Know

Our stores, call centers or sites may contact you regarding your order.

## Call Centers

When you contact our Call Center with a question about a product, order status or billing issue you may be asked for information that identifies you -- along with additional information we need to help us promptly answer your question. This includes your name, address and a phone number where we can reach you. We may keep this information to assist you in the future.

## Online Registration

Registration is an optional service. You do not have to register to browse or shop online. When you register, you are asked for personal information such as your name, address, phone number, email address, a password that you select, and optionally, your interests. Your registration information may be used to help make your online shopping quicker and easier, by pre-filling certain parts of your shopping information. When you register you will also have the opportunity to sign up for future marketing information from True Value.

## Passwords

If you choose to register on this site you will be asked to create a username and password. In order to further protect your personal information, please do not share your password with anyone else. If you wish to cancel a password, or if you become aware of any loss, theft or unauthorized use of your password, please Contact Us.

No “phishing” allowed. We will **never** request your password, user name, credit card information or other personal data through email. This practice, called "phishing", is a scam designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an email that looks like it is from True Value requesting this type of personal information, please delete it.

## Privacy Preferences / Opt-Out 

As a registered user, you may request to see the personal information that we have about you. To access your profile information at any time, go to [My Account](https://www.truevalue.com/user/login.jsp?dest=%2Fuser%2Fmain.jsp).

To unsubscribe from email marketing communications, please select the 'Unsubscribe' link located at the bottom of that particular email message.Since True Value stores are individually owned and operated, you may have to unsubscribe from each store that you receive email from.

Although you may have opted not to receive marketing communications, you may still get order confirmations, product recall notices or other order-related communications. 

## General

Our website uses Secure Sockets Layering (SSL) to encrypt your personal credit information, including your credit card number, before it travels over the Internet. SSL technology is the industry standard for secure online transactions. Because we use SSL, placing an order online at our website is just as safe as giving your credit card number over the phone. 

Want to know how to identify a secure website? Look at the address of the page. Secure pages will appear with an address that starts with "https://" rather than the standard "http://".

## Information About Others

In order to process and / or deliver your order, we may share information with participating True Value retailers and other companies who require it: 

  1. 1\. To ship the order and confirm delivery
  2. 2\. To identify or resolve technical problems or Customer Service issues
  3. 3\. As required by law and to comply with a court order or other legal process
  4. 4\. To respond to claims that your personalized messages violate the rights of third parties
  5. 5\. To protect the rights or property of True Value Company and its affiliates

## Protecting Children's Privacy

We recognize the importance of protecting privacy where children are involved. We will not sell items ordered to anyone we know to be under the age of 18 and if you are under the age of 18, you should not submit orders through our websites or mobile services. We will not collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13 and if you are under the age of 13, you should not submit any personal information to us. We ask that you only use our website or mobile services with the a parent or guardian. If a child has provided our website with personally identifiable information, we ask that a parent or guardian contact us. 

## Your California Privacy Rights 

If you live in California and have an established business relationship with us, you can request a list of the personal information we have shared with third parties for their marketing purposes. We will also give you a list of the third parties that have received your information. You can make a request one time each year.

To exercise your rights, you can email us or write to us. Mention in your letter that you are making a "California Shine the Light" inquiry. We will respond within 30 days. 

## Controlling Online Interest-Based Ads 

We sometimes work with online advertising vendors to provide you with relevant and useful ads. This may include ads served on our websites or mobile services. This may also include ads served on other companies websites. These ads may be based on information collected by us or third parties. For example, information a third party collects when you register for a website, like your zip code. This might be used to target an ad for people in your area. These ads may also be based on your activities on our websites or on third party websites. 

To opt out of having your online behavior collected for advertising purposes, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). 

## Information Sharing

**With third parties who perform services on our behalf.**  
We share information with our service providers, such as our delivery service providers who ship and deliver your online orders. We might also authorize our service providers to collect information on our behalf. Some service providers may be located outside of the United States. We might also share information with the vendors and manufacturers of our products and services to respond to your reviews and questions. We may also share information with companies that provide support services to us (such as a printer, mailing house or web host) or that help us market our products and services. These companies may need information about you in order to perform their functions.

**To offer financial products.**  
We use service providers to offer financial products, such as the True Value credit card. We may share personal information about our consumers with these service providers in order to provide you with tailored information about products and services and special offers. These service providers also have their own privacy statements that set out the manner in which they will collect, use and disclose personal information. We encourage you to review each service provider's privacy statement at the time you submit your application for such financial products. 

## Sale of Business

If some or all of the business assets of our websites are sold or transferred, we would generally transfer the corresponding information about our customers. We also may retain a copy of that customer's information. In addition, if all or part of our business is sold or otherwise transferred, we may sell or transfer our customer information as part of that transaction.

## Legal

For the protection of our websites and others, we may disclose information you provide on our websites. Especially when we believe disclosure is necessary to comply with the law; to enforce or apply our Conditions of Use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of our websites, our users or others.

## Tracking Tools

Our websites use cookies to create a more personalized shopping experience for you when visiting our site. They let us "remember" information about your preferences and site viewing session(s), and allow you to move within areas of our websites without reintroducing yourself. 

True Value Company uses a third party to place cookies on your computer to collect non-personally identifiable information about your operating system, browser version, IP Address, and geo-location if you are using a mobile device. We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with relevant online display advertising tailored to your interests. To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising, [click here](http://dtmc.truevalue.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=61961&cname=True%20Value&cmagic=31ea09&clogo=61961.png&loc=us&lang=en-us). 

You may choose to set your Web browser to not accept cookies. However, without enabling your cookies, you will not be able to view, create an account, or make purchases on the True Value site. 

We collect personal and other information about users over time and across different websites when you use this website or service. We also have third parties that collect personal information this way. We or our vendors use several common online tracking tools to collect this information. These may include browser and flash cookies. We may also use web beacons and similar technologies. We use these tools: 

  * To track new visitors to our websites. 
  * To recognize returning customers. 
  * To store your password if you are registered on our websites. 
  * To make product recommendations and provide you with advertising content in which we think you will be interested. As part of this customization, we may observe your behaviors on our mobile services, our websites or on other websites. We may also get information about your browsing history from our trusted business partners and vendors.
  * So we can better understand our audience, our customers, our website visitors and mobile application users, and their respective interests. 
  * To provide correct pricing and ads for the local store you select. 
  * To fulfill purchases made on our website or through our mobile services. 

### Controlling Our Tracking Tools

Your browser may give you the ability to control cookies. How you do so depends on the type of cookie. Certain browsers can be set to reject browser cookies. Flash cookies cannot be controlled through your browser settings. Your mobile device may not give you the ability to control cookies. If you wish to block cookies on our mobile application, you will need to delete the application from your mobile device. If you configure your device to block cookies, you will limit the functionality we can provide when you visit our websites. If you configure to block or delete cookies, not all of the tracking that we have described in this policy will stop. 

**Our "Do Not Track" policy:** Some browsers have a "Do Not Track" feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. These browser features are not uniform, so we are not currently set up to respond to those signals. 

## Third Party Links

Our Sites may include links to the websites of our business partners, vendors and advertisers. Except for the situations explained here in this section, we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your prior consent.

Want to Talk?

If you have additional questions about privacy & security, please Contact Us.

## How to Find Out About Changes to our Official Privacy and Security Statement 

We suggest you check this site periodically for any privacy modifications and effective dates. When you continue to use this website after we post changes, you are accepting the Privacy and Security Statement as modified.

Here's an on-going list of updates to help you to keep track of any changes. 

Last updated: October 2, 2015.

Original date: November 1, 2010.
